JASON TIGHE

Tighe59@gmail.com

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A software engineer with a background in accounting and information systems, skilled at tackling complex problems using quick wit and a calm mentality. Passionate about growth and creativity with experience in accounting and information systems. Approach each project with a well rounded and fresh perspective.

SKILLS

Javascript - Python - SQL - Vue - React - Boostrap - Express - Node.Js - Django" - MongoDB - MySQL - PostgreSQL

TECHNICAL PROJECT EXPERIENCE

CovidTRKR: a web-app that allows a user to record their symptoms as well as use the google api to locate the nearest facility Funk!: a social-media app used to express the users thoughts and experiences anonymously through posts DinoRunner: a Javascript infinite runner game using css and javascript for basic physics.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Marketsmith Inc. Cedar Knolls, NJ

Accounting Associate January 2021 – Current

- Prepared and tracked monthly retainer and prebill.
 - Reconciled and closed campaigns in a timely fashion.
 - Generated and analyzed payable and receivable aging reports to maintain an accurate record of accounts.
- Applied cash according to the previous week's payment batch.
- Accurately reconciled and reported on credit card expenditures on a monthly basis.

Commonbond New York, NY

Staff Accountant January 2019 – February 2020

- Developed and designed disbursement reconciliation used to identify control weakness and control process.
- Accurately making month end accrual journal entries for AR activity
- Generate pivot table for Daily Transaction Report, then review for unforeseen activity.
- Accurately reconcile bank activity on a daily basis.
- Update Final Disbursement Reports to verify outstanding checks and re-disbursements for borrowers who have refinanced
- Pulled loan docs through Retool and AWS, review for accuracy, and send loan documents for
- sales through FTP, submit any errors using JIRA to the tech team.
- Used NetSuite to generate invoices for clients and referral partners
- Record any funds received that may be a refund or reimbursement for the borrower into a tracker.
- Put together a report to alert the servicer to update borrowers accounts accordingly and submit a bug report and update any cards on the Kanban board.

Generator Media & Analytics

New York, NY

Finance and Accounting Coordinator

July 2016 - January 2019

- Provided expenditure reports to media teams for strategic planning
- Reconciled accounts and met with Media teams to determine if any credits were owed to us or the clients
- Analyzed and updated client and vendor information, decreasing the of number of returned checks

Mt. Laurel, NJ Ruotolo, Spewak & Co

November 2014 – May 2015

- Prepared 1040, 1065, 1120, and 990 client tax returns.
- Performed auditing fieldwork through systems analysis and creating/referencing work papers.
- Trained new interns and associates how to complete tax returns using Pro Series and Adobe Acrobat.

EDUCATION

Tax Intern

B.S. Accounting, Management Information Systems | ROWAN UNIVERSITY

Glassboro, NJ